A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1973-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1973-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.761
This collection consists of 25,200 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was forwarded to the library on 29 July 1976.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
The papers consist of: general and University committees files; and, American Council on Education files.
Organization
SERIES I: General Files, 1973-1974, Boxes 1-47
SERIES II: University Committees, 1973-1974, Boxes 48-51
SERIES III: American Council on Education, Box 52
Contents List
- Series I: General Records
  - "A - Al" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - "Am" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - "An - Az" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Academic Deans 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Admissions - General 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Admissions 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Admissions Reports 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Admissions - Personnel 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Air Force ROTC 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Day 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association - General 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Fund 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Alumni News 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association - Houston Chapter 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association - Washington Chapter 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Alumni - Medical 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - American Association of State Colleges and Universities 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - American Association of University Professors 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - American Council on Education 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - American Council on Education - Higher Education and National Affairs 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Annual Report of the President 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Anthropology 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "A - Z" 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Army ROTC 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Army - JAG School 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Architecture - General 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Art - General 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Art - Bayly Museum 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Art Commissions 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Asian Studies Consortium 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Colleges 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities (AAU) 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - AAU - Executive Committee 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - AAU - Membership Committee 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - AAU Fall Meeting - 22 October 1973 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - AAU Council on Federal Relations 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - AAU Spring Meeting - 23 - 24 April 1974 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - Association of Commonwealth Universities 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Astronomy 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - General 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Personnel 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Football 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Finances 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Football, Commonwealth Day 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Football, Invitations to Games 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Football, V. M. I. Game - 8 September 1973 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Football, North Carolina State - 15 September 1973 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Football, Duke Game - 29 September 1973 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Football, Vanderbilt Game - 6 October 1973 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Football, Virginia Tech Game - 20 October 1973 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Football, Commonwealth Day - 27 October 1973 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Football, North Carolina - 3 November 1973 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Football, Maryland Game - 10 November 1973 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Football, West Virginia - 17 November 1973 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - Basketball 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Athletics - ACC 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Athletics - NCAA 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Athletics - Touchdown Club 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Atlantic Council of the United States 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Atomic Energy Commission 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Attorney General (State) 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Audit Reports 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Automated Data Processing (State) 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - "B - Bm" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 9)
  - "Bn - Bz" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 9)
  - Biology - General 1973-1974 (Box 9)
  - Black Student Alliance 1973-1974 (Box 9)
  - Budget - Analysis 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Budget - Capital Outlay 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Budget - Requests 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Buildings and Grounds - General 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Bursar 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Business and Finance 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Business Manager 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Business Manager - Transportation 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - "Ca - Ck" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - "Cl - Cz" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Career Planning and Placement 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Cavalier Daily 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Center for Advanced Studies 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Center for Textual and Editorial Studies in Humanistic Sources (3 folders) 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Chemistry 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Chronicles of Higher Education 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Civil Defense 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Civil Rights - General 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Classics 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Clinch Valley College 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Clinch Valley College - Personnel 1973-1974 (Box 12)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1973-1974 (Box 12)
  - College Entrance Examination Board 1973-1974 (Box 12)
  - Commerce - General 1973-1974 (Box 12)
  - Community Colleges 1973-1974 (Box 12)
  - Comptroller 1973-1974 (Box 12)
  - Comptroller (State) 1973-1974 (Box 12)
  - Condolences 1973-1974 (Box 12)
  - Central Virginia Consortium 1973-1974 (Box 12)
  - Consortium for Continuing Higher Education in Northern Virginia 1973-1974 (Box 13)
  - Consortium - Shenandoa Valley 1973-1974 (Box 13)
  - Consortium Western Region 1973-1974 (Box 13)
  - Consultative Resource Center on School Desegregation at U.Va. 1973-1974 (Box 13)
  - Continuing Education - General 1973-1974 (Box 13)
  - Continuing Education - Personnel 1973-1974 (Box 13)
  - Continuing Education - Madison Center 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Continuing Education - F. B. I. National Academy 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Continuing Education - Hampton Roads Center (folder empty) 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Center for Continuing Education in Northern Virginia 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Continuing Education - Patrick Henry 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Continuing Education - Roanoke Center 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Council of Southern Universities 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Council of Presidents 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Council to the President for Special Development 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Criminal Justice Coordinating Council 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - "Da - De" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - "Df - Dz" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Danforth Foundation 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Data Processing 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Degrees 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - Development 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - Development Council 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - Drama 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - Economics 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - Education - General 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - Education - Personnel 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - Education - Search for a Dean 1973-1974 (Box 16)
  - Endowment Fund 1973-1974 (Box 16)
  - William A. Elwood 1973-1974 (Box 16)
  - Engineering and Buildings 1973-1974 (Box 16)
  - Engineering - General 1973-1974 (Box 16)
  - English 1973-1974 (Box 16)
  - Equal Opportunity Programs - 1973-1974 1973-1974 (Box 17)
  - Engineering - Personnel 1973-1974 (Box 17)
  - Enrollment 1973-1974 (Box 17)
  - Environmental Science 1973-1974 (Box 17)
  - Equal Opportunity Programs - 1972-1973 1973-1974 (Box 17)
  - Equal Opportunity Programs - 1971 - 1972 1973-1974 (Box 18)
  - Equal Opportunity Programs - 1970 - 1971 1973-1974 (Box 18)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 18)
  - Faculty - General 1973-1974 (Box 18)
  - Faculty - Promotions 1973-1974 (Box 18)
  - Faculty Orientation and Reception - 1973 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Faculty Orientation and Reception - 1973-1974 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - General 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Faculty Meetings 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Bayly - Tiffany (folder empty) 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Dupont Regional 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Fulbright 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Wallerstein 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Federal Executive Institute 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Financial Aid to Students 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Ford Foundation 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - French Literature and General Linguistics 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 20)
  - Carroll A. Gardner - Special Assistant to the President 1973-1974 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly 1973-1974 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly - Shaner Report 1973-1974 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly - Report of the Commission on Higher Education 1973-1974 (Box 20a)
  - General Assembly - Commission on Higher Education 1973-1974 (Box 20a)
  - George Mason College 1973-1974 (Box 20a)
  - Germanic Literature 1973-1974 (Box 20a)
  - Gifts and Grants Correspondence 1973-1974 (Box 20a)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office - Education 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office - Administration 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Management Study (folder empty) 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Advisory Board 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - Graduate Business Sponsors 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - Graphics 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - Graves Mountain Conference - Calendar 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - Guggenheim Foundation 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - "H" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 22)
  - Harvard Graduate Society Council 1973-1974 (Box 22)
  - Higher Education Act of 1965 1973-1974 (Box 22)
  - Highway Department 1973-1974 (Box 22)
  - Highway Research Council 1973-1974 (Box 22)
  - History 1973-1974 (Box 22)
  - Honor System and Honor Committee 1973-1974 (Box 22)
  - Housing 1973-1974 (Box 22)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 22)
  - Information Services 1973-1974 (Box 22)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Institute of Government 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Institutional Analysis 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - International Students Office 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "A" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "B" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "C" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "E" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "F" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "G" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "H" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "I" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "J" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "K" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "M" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "N" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "P" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "R" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "S" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "T" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "U" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "V" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "W" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "Z" 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 24)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation - General 1973-1974 (Box 24)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation - Monthly Reports 1973-1974 (Box 24)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation - Minutes 1973-1974 (Box 24)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation - Committees Meetings 1973-1974 (Box 24)
  - The Jefferson Society 1973-1974 (Box 24)
  - Judiciary Committee 1973-1974 (Box 24)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 24)
  - Kenan Charitable Trust 1973-1974 (Box 24)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 25)
  - Law - General 1973-1974 (Box 25)
  - Law Admissions - "A - Z" 1973-1974 (Box 25)
  - Law - Personnel 1973-1974 (Box 25)
  - Law Enforcement Education Program 1973-1974 (Box 25)
  - Lectures 1973-1974 (Box 25)
  - Legal Advisor 1973-1974 (Box 26)
  - Legal Estates 1973-1974 (Box 26)
  - Library - General 1973-1974 (Box 26)
  - Library - Personnel 1973-1974 (Box 26)
  - Library - Associates 1973-1974 (Box 26)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 27)
  - McGregor Fund 1973-1974 (Box 27)
  - "Ma - Me" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 27)
  - "Mi - Mz" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 27)
  - Madison Hall 1973-1974 (Box 28)
  - Marine Science 1973-1974 (Box 28)
  - Mary Washington College 1973-1974 (Box 28)
  - Mathematics 1973-1974 (Box 28)
  - Central Virginia Mental Health Consortium 1973-1974 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center - General 1973-1974 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center - Hospital 1973-1974 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center - Hospital Personnel 1973-1974 (Box 28)
  - Medical School - General 1973-1974 (Box 28)
  - Medical School - Admissions "A - Z" 1973-1974 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center - Nursing 1973-1974 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center - Nursing Personnel 1973-1974 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center - Monthly Statistical Reports 1973-1974 (Box 29)
  - Medical Center - Reports on Current Operations 1973-1974 (Box 29)
  - Medical Center - Operating Budget and Reports 1973-1974 (Box 29)
  - Music 1973-1974 (Box 29)
  - "Na" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 29)
  - "Ne - Nz" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 29)
  - NASA 1973-1974 (Box 29)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - Circular Letters 1973-1974 (Box 29)
  - NASULGC - Office of Institutional Research 1973-1974 (Box 29)
  - NASULGC 1973-1974 (Box 30)
  - NASULGC - International Letters 1973-1974 (Box 30)
  - NASULGC - Advancement of Public Negro Colleges 1973-1974 (Box 30)
  - NASULGC - ad hoc Committee on Criteria for Membership in the Association 1973-1974 (Box 30)
  - National Commission on Accrediting 1973-1974 (Box 30)
  - National Defense Education Act 1973-1974 (Box 30)
  - National Science Foundation - General 1973-1974 (Box 30)
  - National Science Foundation - Institutional Grants for Science 1973-1974 (Box 30)
  - National Science Foundation - Advisory Committee for Institutional Relations 1973-1974 (Box 30)
  - National Science Foundation - Science Development Plan 1973-1974 (Box 30)
  - National Science Foundation - Committee on Science Development Plan 1973-1974 (Box 31)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities 1973-1974 (Box 31)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation 1973-1974 (Box 31)
  - National War College 1973-1974 (Box 31)
  - Navy - ROTC 1973-1974 (Box 31)
  - Secretary of the Navy Advisory Board, Education and Training (SABET) 1973-1974 (Box 32)
  - Navy League of the United States 1973-1974 (Box 32)
  - Newcomb Hall 1973-1974 (Box 32)
  - Newcomb Hall Bookstore, Anderson's Bookstore - 1970 - 1974 1973-1974 (Box 32)
  - Newcomen Society 1973-1974 (Box 32)
  - Newcomen Society 1973-1974 (Box 32)
  - Newcomen Dinner List during Sesquecentennial - 23 January 1969 1973-1974 (Box 32)
  - New Federalist Papers 1973-1974 (Box 32)
  - Office Invoices 1973-1974 (Box 33)
  - Office Invoices - Travel 1973-1974 (Box 34)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 34)
  - Oceanic Educational Foundation 1973-1974 (Box 34)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa 1973-1974 (Box 34)
  - "P - PH" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 34)
  - "Pi - Pz" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 34)
  - Parking and Transit 1973-1974 (Box 35)
  - Personnel - General 1973-1974 (Box 35)
  - Personnel - Employee Relations 1973-1974 (Box 35)
  - Personnel - Hospital Insurance Plan 1973-1974 (Box 35)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1973-1974 (Box 35)
  - Philosophy 1973-1974 (Box 35)
  - Physics - General 1973-1974 (Box 35)
  - Physics - Personnel 1973-1974 (Box 35)
  - Division of Planning (State) 1973-1974 (Box 35)
  - Planning Department 1973-1974 (Box 35)
  - Project Status Reports 1973-1974 (Box 35)
  - Provost 1973-1974 (Box 36)
  - Public Affairs 1973-1974 (Box 36)
  - Purchasing 1973-1974 (Box 36)
  - Purchasing and Supply 1973-1974 (Box 36)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 36)
  - Questionnaires and Inquiries 1973-1974 (Box 36)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 36)
  - Recommendations - "A - Z" 1973-1974 (Box 36)
  - Registrar - General 1973-1974 (Box 37)
  - Registrar - Student Reports 1973-1974 (Box 37)
  - C. Tom Reese - Assistant to the President 1973-1974 (Box 37)
  - Rehabilitation Center 1973-1974 (Box 37)
  - Religious Studies 1973-1974 (Box 37)
  - Report to the University Community from President Edgar F. Shannon, Jr. - December 1970 - December 1971 1973-1974 (Box 37)
  - ROTC 1973-1974 (Box 37)
  - "S - Sl" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 37)
  - "Sm - Sz" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 37)
  - Salaries 1973-1974 (Box 37)
  - Administrative Salaries - A Rank-Order Distribution 1973-1974 (Box 37)
  - Security 1973-1974 (Box 38)
  - Security - University Police - Calvin T. Thompson 1973-1974 (Box 38)
  - Security - Chaffin Case 1973-1974 (Box 38)
  - Security - Chaffin Case - Black sit-in, 23 - 24 March 1972 1973-1974 (Box 38)
  - Senate - University 1973-1974 (Box 39)
  - Senate - University - Minutes 1973-1974 (Box 39)
  - Seven Society 1973-1974 (Box 39)
  - Slavic Languages and Literature 1973-1974 (Box 39)
  - Sociology and Anthropology 1973-1974 (Box 39)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools 1973-1974 (Box 39)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (Permanent) 1973-1974 (Box 40)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - Southern Fellowship Fund 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - Southern Regional Education Board 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - Southern University Conference 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - Spanish and Portuguese Literature 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - Special Programs 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - Special Programs - Action 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - Speech Communication 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - Speech Pathoogy and Audiology 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - Speeches by President Shannon for the current year 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - List of speeches given by Mr. Shannon since becoming President 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - Speeches - Material for Speeches (Permanent File) 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - Sponsored Programs 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - State Board of Education 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - State Council of Higher Education - Visitation, 4 June 1974 1973-1974 (Box 42)
  - State Council of Higher Education 1973-1974 (Box 42)
  - State Council of Higher Education - Mission Statement Business 1973-1974 (Box 42)
  - State Council of Higher Education 1973-1974 (Box 43)
  - State Department of Education 1973-1974 (Box 43)
  - Student Affairs 1973-1974 (Box 43)
  - Student Affairs - Student Luncheons 1973-1974 (Box 43)
  - Student Council (2 folders) 1973-1974 (Box 44)
  - Student Council - Self Defense 1973-1974 (Box 44)
  - Student Council - Minutes of Meetings 1973-1974 (Box 44)
  - Student Health Department 1973-1974 (Box 44)
  - Student Legal Forum 1973-1974 (Box 44)
  - Summer Session - 1973 1973-1974 (Box 44)
  - Summer Session - 1974 1973-1974 (Box 45)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 45)
  - Alton L. Taylor 1973-1974 (Box 45)
  - Taloe Murphy Institute 1973-1974 (Box 45)
  - Treasurer 1973-1974 (Box 45)
  - Tuition and Fees 1973-1974 (Box 45)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 45)
  - United Sates Congress 1973-1974 (Box 45)
  - United Sates Department of Health, Education, and Welfare 1973-1974 (Box 45)
  - United States Department of State 1973-1974 (Box 46)
  - United States Naval Academy 1973-1974 (Box 46)
  - University Center in Virginia 1973-1974 (Box 46)
  - University Hall 1973-1974 (Box 46)
  - University Editor 1973-1974 (Box 46)
  - University Press of Virginia 1973-1974 (Box 46)
  - University Printing Office 1973-1974 (Box 46)
  - University Housing - "Morea" 1973-1974 (Box 46)
  - University Relations 1973-1974 (Box 46)
  - Universities Research Association 1973-1974 (Box 46)
  - University Research Policy Council 1973-1974 (Box 46)
  - University Union 1973-1974 (Box 46)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 46)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1973-1974 (Box 47)
  - Virginia Commission on Higher Education Facilities 1973-1974 (Box 47)
  - Virginia Historical Society 1973-1974 (Box 47)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1973-1974 (Box 47)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce 1973-1974 (Box 47)
  - Virginia Status of University Students 1973-1974 (Box 47)
  - Virginia Student Aid Foundation 1973-1974 (Box 47)
  - "W - Wh" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 47)
  - "Wi - Wz" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 47)
  - "X - Y - Z" Miscellaneous 1973-1974 (Box 47)
- Series II: University Committees, 1973 - 1974
  - Ad hoc Committee: Search for a Dean of Admissions 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Search Committee for a Dean of the School of Education 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Ad hoc Committee: Search for a Dean of the Faculty 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Ad hoc Committee: Search for a Dean of Continuing Education 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Academic Computing 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Admissions 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award (folder empty) 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Arboretum 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Architectural Advisory 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Athletic Advisory Council 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Boxing 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Calendar and Scheduling 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Catalogue 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Environment 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Fraternities 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Fulbright Grants 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Future of the University 1973-1974 (Box 48)
  - Future of the University 1973-1974 (Box 49)
  - Educational and Employment Opportunities, Obligations, and Rights (2 folders) 1973-1974 (Box 49)
  - Educational and Employment Opportunities, Obligations, and Rights - Rotch Committee 1973-1974 (Box 49)
  - Future of the University 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - Gwathmey Award 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - Housing 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - Inauguration Committee 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - Institutional Analysis 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - International Students 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - Thomas Jefferson Award 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - Lectures - Page-Barbour and Richard 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - Library 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - Master Plan 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - Museum 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - Names 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - Processions 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - Public Occasions 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - Radiation Safety 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - Rhodes Scholarship 1973-1974 (Box 50)
  - ROTC Affairs 1973-1974 (Box 51)
  - Security and General Safety 1973-1974 (Box 51)
  - Student Activities 1973-1974 (Box 51)
  - Student Health 1973-1974 (Box 51)
  - Student Rights and Responsibilities 1973-1974 (Box 51)
  - Summer Grants 1973-1974 (Box 51)
  - Summer Session 1973-1974 (Box 51)
  - Traffic and Parking 1973-1974 (Box 51)
  - University Union 1973-1974 (Box 51)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1973-1974 (Box 51)
  - Virginia Status of University Students 1973-1974 (Box 51)
- Series III, American Council on Education
  - American Council on Education - Report on THE NEED FOR A NATIONAL STUDY OF INTERCOLLEGIATE ATHLETICS (see AAU - Executive Committee) 1973-1974 (Box 52)
  - American Council on Education - Appendices to the above report 1973-1974 (Box 52)